$author=audio of lesson 1 chapter 1 book 1$ In this lesson, we're going to
be talking about finance. And
$author=Elena$ one of the most important aspects
of finance is interest.
$author=Mom$ When I go to a bank or some
other lending institution
$author=David$ to borrow money, the bank is happy
to give me that money. But then I'm
$author=audio of lesson 1 chapter 1 book 1$ going to be paying the bank for the
privilege of using their money. And that
$author=Marry$ amount of money that I pay the bank is
called interest. Likewise, if I put money
$author=Erric$ in a savings account or I purchase a
certificate of deposit, the bank just
$author=Elena$ doesn't put my money in a little box
and leave it there until later. They take
$author=Tom$ my money and lend it to someone
else. So they are using my money.
$author=audio of lesson 1 chapter 1 book 1$ The bank has to pay me for the privilege
of using my money.
$author=Tony$ Now what makes banks
profitable is the rate
$author=Erric$ that they charge people to use the bank's
money is higher than the rate that they